Guide to the Clark, Hall, and Peck and White Brothers Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Clark, Hall, and Peck and White Brothers records
1860-1982
MS 1820
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1439.5
(2396)
The records consist of abstracts of title, atlases, maps, indices, index card locator files, probate extracts, and ownership files from the Clark, Hall, and Peck and White Brothers, and its predecessors, the most active New Haven law firms in real property law between the 1860s and 1982.
Clark, Hall, and Peck and White Brothers (New Haven, Conn.)
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift and purchase from James A. Nugent, 2003.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Separated Materials
Atlases and maps from Clark, Hall, and; Peck are also located in the Map Collection, Yale University Library.
Biographical / Historical
White Brothers, and Clark, Hall and Peck were the two New Haven law firms most active in real property law between the 1860s and 1982. The firm of White Brothers dates from the 1820s, when Henry White was admitted to the New Haven County Bar. White married Martha Sherman, the granddaughter of Roger Sherman, in 1830. Four of his sons eventually joined him in the practice of law. Clark, Hall and Peck was founded in the 1890s by James Gardiner Clark, Henry A. L. Hall, and George Leete Peck. White Brothers and Clark, Hall and Peck merged to form a single law firm in 1974. The firm of Clark, Hall and Peck and White Brothers dissolved in 1982.
Scope and Contents
The Clark, Hall, and Peck and White Brothers records consist of abstracts of title, index card locator files, atlases, maps, probate extracts, project files, and grantor-grantee files. The collection primarily deals with properties located in the cities and towns of New Haven County, Connecticut including New Haven, Ansonia, Bethany, Branford, Cheshire, Clinton, Derby, Durham, East Haven, Guilford, Hamden, Killingworth, Madison, Meriden, Milford, Naugatuck, North Branford, North Haven, Orange, Oxford, Prospect, Seymour, Wallingford, West Haven, and Woodbridge. Properties located in a number of other Connecticut cities and towns are also indexed by these materials. Abstracts of title are the most numerous types of documentation found in the records. The type and amount of materials relating to each property vary significantly.
A title search is usually performed by an attorney in conjunction with the sale or mortgage of property. The searcher reviews the records contained in various offices of town clerks in order to reveal any encumbrances upon the property. The types of records maintained by town clerks would include deeds, mortgages, liens, rights of way, easements, restrictions, taxes, or other matters that might affect the use of the property. By examining the public records, the attorney could provide his client, usually the purchaser, with a "snapshot" of the legal status of the property, what interest did the seller have authority to convey, what encumbrances would there be if the property was purchased, and whether the buyer could use the property for the purpose he intended. In addition to recorded instruments such as deeds and mortgages, searchers also rely on probate records, vital statistics, and court records, since they disclose other obligations affecting the property. Generally, each instrument involved in a title search shows the owner [grantor or seller], the buyer [grantee], the date, the volume and page where it is recorded in the town clerk's office, the legal description of the property, and the particular terms of the instrument.
Arrangement
Arranged in three series: I. White Brothers, 1880s-1982. II. Clark, Hall and Peck, 1890s-1982. III. Indices, Atlases, and Maps, 1860s-1950s.
Abstracts of title; Deeds; Land titles; Real property surveys; Real property; Connecticut; New Haven (Conn.); Atlases; Maps (documents); Clark, Hall, and Peck (New Haven, Conn.); Clark, Hall, and Peck and White Brothers (New Haven, Conn.); White Brothers (New Haven, Conn.)
- White Brothers, 1880s-1982; Series I
  Arrangement
  The records are arranged by city or town.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains abstracts of title searches by the White Brothers law firm, primarily between the 1880s and 1982. Since White Brothers was very involved in real estate transactions (particularly in New Haven County), there is significant documentation of property history, though all properties will not have a record.
  The records are arranged by city, city section, or town and are accessed by locating the street name on a map or card index file. The original document arrangement, as devised by the law firm, has been retained. Material relating to New Haven and its associated sections (Annex, Westville, and Fair Haven) appear first, followed by other Connecticut cities and towns. Within the arrangement of each city, city section, or town, abstracts of title are generally found in order of size of the documentation: folded, flat files, and project files. The amount of materials assembled for each tract determined whether they were gathered in folded bundles (small), flat files (medium), or project files (large). Although the largest number of properties will be represented among the folded bundles, the researcher should also examine the entries under the headings for flat files and project files to ensure that all materials in this series are located.
  The city of New Haven is divided into forty-three districts, as shown on the Map of New Haven and Suburbs (Series III, Box 2269). In addition, there are two other areas associated with New Haven that are also shown on this map. The Annex (the area east of New Haven Harbor and the Quinnipiac River)is District 50, and Westville (to the northwest of New Haven) is District 70. The properties in Fair Haven are depicted in a plot map book in Box 387. Other Connecticut cities and towns are arranged alphabetically after the New Haven flat and project files.
  In the case of New Haven addresses, the map should be examined closely to determine which district a particular street has been assigned. Sections of streets may be assigned to different districts depending upon which side of the street a property is located, or the specific address. After locating the district number, the researcher should look in the box listing under that number to find the box containing the desired street. Within the box of folded abstracts, the researcher will generally find the properties arranged alphabetically by street name.
  The researcher should be particularly aware that the abstracts are "snapshots" of the status of property titles at a particular time and that property configurations and addresses may have changed over time. In some cases, the finding aid provides a range of several numerical addresses rather than a single address. In other cases, materials may be found in "non-street number" files, a term used when abstracts indicate a street name, but not a particular number on the street. In addition, properties that abutted two streets may have abstracts under headings for either or both streets.
  In addition to the folded files, researchers are encouraged to review the listing of flat files, both alphabetical (beginning with box 439) and non-alphabetical (beginning with box 450) to ascertain if there is any further documentation. Finally, there are five project files to consult (beginning with box 467): Dixwell-Whalley Avenue (properties located behind Yale University's Payne Whitney gymnasium taken to construct a public housing project), Interstate 91 (properties utilized to create Interstate 91), Oak Street Connector (properties used to link the Yale-New Haven Hospital with Interstates 91 and 95), Tontine Hotel (intersection of Church and Court Streets), and the Yale Bowl.
  Information on properties that are not located in New Haven, or its associated sections (Annex, Westville, and Fair Haven), are found in the files for other Connecticut cites and towns. These materials follow the New Haven files (beginning in box 483) and are arranged alphabetically by city or town name. The records for Ansonia, Bethany, Branford, Cheshire, Clinton, Derby, Durham, Guilford, Killingworth, Madison, North Branford, Orange, Wallingford, and Woodbridge consist of index card locator files, folded abstracts, miscellaneous records, and flat files. To find the file for a particular address, the researcher should consult the index card locator boxes which are arranged alphabetically by street. If a card for a particular address exists, it will have a number assigned by the law firm in the top corner of the card corresponding to the folded abstract or flat file. Using this number, the researcher would look in the finding aid under the appropriate town to determine whether the abstract is in a box containing folded files or flat files. As with the New Haven materials, the researcher must review folded, flat files (numbered/ unnumbered or alphabetical), and miscellaneous files to obtain all materials related to the specific property.
  Documentation from East Haven, Hamden, Milford, North Haven, and West Haven contain only folded abstracts, miscellaneous records, and flat files. There is no index card locator. The folded abstracts are arranged alphabetically by street. The flat files for these towns are arranged alphabetically.
  A partial index to grantor (seller)-grantee (purchaser) files appears towards the end of the White Brothers series. If an individual or company owned several parcels of property, it was sometimes more convenient for the law firm to arrange the abstracts together by the name of the grantor (seller) rather than to keep them in the district and street order arrangement. The alphabetical index by grantor surname is found at the front of the first box of the grantor-grantee files located in box 935.
  Unidentified flat files and probate records are located at the end of the town or the series.
  Oversize indices and map books that may be useful in research are found in Series III.
  - New Haven
    - Folded abstracts of title
      - District 1
        - Beers Street, Ellsworth Avenue, Park Street, Sherman Avenue, Sherman Court, Winthrop Avenue (Box 1)
        - Boulevard, Gill Street, Hotchkiss Street, Howe Street (Box 2)
        - Chapel Street (Street addresses 1179 through 1523) (Box 3)
        - Chapel Street (Street addresses 1531 through 1639, non-street number files) (Box 4)
        - Day Street, Stanley Street (Box 5)
        - Dwight Street, Kensington Street, Norton Street, Orchard Street (Box 6)
        - Edgewood Avenue (Street addresses 16 through 468-470, non-street number files) (Box 7)
      - District 2
        - Beers Street, Boulevard, Brownell Street, Dwight Street, Ellsworth Avenue (Box 8)
        - Edgewood Avenue (Odd number street addresses 13 through 513) (Box 9)
        - Elm Street (Even number street addresses 312 through 540) (Box 10)
        - Elm Street (Even number street addresses 544 through 966) (Box 11)
        - Elm Street (Non-street number files), Garden Street, Lynwood Place (Box 12)
        - Orchard Street, Park Street, Platt Street (Box 13)
        - Hobart Street, Howe Street, Hubinger Street, Maple Street (Box 14)
        - Pendleton Street, Sherman Avenue, Winthrop Avenue, Norton Street (Box 15)
        - Kensington Street (Box 16)
      - District 3
        - Argonne Street, Baldwin Place, Boulevard, Broadway, Brownell Street (Box 17)
        - Dwight Street, Howe Street (Box 18)
        - Ellsworth Avenue, Hobart Street, Hubinger Street, Norton Street, Sherman Avenue, West Park Avenue (Box 19)
        - Elm Street (North side, odd number street addresses 343 through 695) (Box 20)
        - Elm Street (North side, odd number street addresses 701 through 995, non-street number files), Garden Street, Orchard Street (Box 21)
        - Pendleton Street, University Place, Winthrop Avenue (Box 22)
        - Whalley Avenue (South side, even number street addresses 14 through 368) (Box 23)
        - Whalley Avenue (South side, even number street addresses 374 through 762, non-street number files) (Box 24)
        - Whalley Avenue (South side, non-street number files, and "Elm City Park" also known as "Hamilton Park") (Box 25)
      - District 4
        - Anita Street, Jewell Street, Whalley Avenue (North side, non-street number files) (Box 26)
        - Blake Street, Diamond Street, "Fairlawn Manor" (Box 27)
        - Boulevard, County Street, Dickerman Street (Box 28)
        - Hudson Street (Box 29)
        - Norton Street (Box 30)
        - Carmel Street, Onyx Street, Sperry Street (Box 31)
        - Ellsworth Avenue, Osborn Avenue, Ruby Street, Whittlesey Avenue (Box 32)
        - Fitch Street, Goffe Terrace, Goff Street (Box 33)
        - Orchard Street, Winthrop Avenue (Box 34)
        - Sherman Avenue, Young Street (Box 35)
        - Whalley Avenue (North side, odd number street addresses 21 through 385) (Box 36)
        - Whalley Avenue (North side, odd number street addresses 399 through 801-811, non-street number files) (Box 37)
      - District 5
        - Chapel Street, Elm Street, Park Street, York Street (Box 38)
      - District 6
        - Admiral Street, York Street (Box 39)
        - Ashmun Street, (West side, even number street addresses 12-14-16 through 320-326, non-street number files) (Box 40)
        - Bristol Street, Broadway (Box 41)
        - Gregory Street, Charles Street (Box 42)
        - Eaton Street (Box 43)
        - Dixwell Avenue (West side, even number street addresses 26 through 316) (Box 44)
        - Dixwell Avenue (West side, non-street number files) (Box 45)
        - Dixwell Avenue (East side, odd number street addresses 7 through 329) (Box 46)
        - Dixwell Avenue (East side, non-street number files), Foote Street (Box 47)
        - Goffe Street (Box 48)
        - Henry Street (Box 49)
        - Lake Place, Orchard Street, Pierpont Court, Townsend Street (Box 50)
        - Munson Street, Winter Street (Box 51)
        - Webster Street, York Square (Box 52)
      - District 7
        - Ashmun Street, Loomis Place (Box 53)
        - Autumn Street, Bristol Street, Canner Street, Cliff Street, Compton Street, Division Street, Ogden Street (Box 54)
        - Canal Street, Lawrence Street (Box 55)
        - East Rock Road, Edwards Street, Grove Street, Hillhouse Avenue (Box 56)
        - Edgehill Road, Starr Street, Temple Street (Box 57)
        - Gregory Street, Street Ronan Street, Street RonanTerrace, Webster Street, Woodland Street (Box 58)
        - Highland Street, Lock Street, Munson Street, Prospect Place, Tilton Street, Trumbull Street, Hillside Place (Box 59)
        - Mansfield Street (Box 60)
        - Whitney Avenue (West side, even number street addresses 20-32 through 730-738) (Box 61)
        - Huntington Street, Whitney Avenue (West side, non-street number files) (Box 62)
        - Prospect Street (Sequential street numbers, street addresses 88-90 through 701) (Box 63)
        - Prospect Street (Non-street number files) (Box 64)
        - Sachem Street, Sheffield Avenue (Box 65)
        - Sheldon Terrace (Box 66)
        - Winchester Avenue (West side, sequential street addresses 2-10 through 200), East and West Winchester Avenue (non-street number files) (Box 67)
        - Winchester Avenue (East side, odd number street addresses 5-15 through 513) (Box 68)
        - Winchester Avenue (East side, odd number street addresses, 517-519 through 767) (Box 69)
      - District 8
        - Bassett Street, Beaver Pond, Cherry Ann Street, Diamond Street, Pelham Lane, Prescott Street, Rock View Terrace, Wellington Road, West Hazel Street (Box 70)
        - Beaver Hill Lane, Colony Road, Fitch Street, Roger White Drive (Box 71)
        - Bellevue Road, County Street, Elizabeth Street (Box 72)
        - Boulevard, Dyer Street, Fournier Street (Box 73)
        - Goffe Street, Goffe Terrace, Henry Street, Hudson Street, West Ivy Street (Box 74)
        - Crescent Street, Dorman Street, Ellsworth Avenue, Fowler Street (Box 75)
        - Dixwell Avenue (West side, street addresses 360-382 through 808-814) (Box 76)
        - Dixwell Avenue (West side, non-street number files) Winthrop Avenue, Glen Road, Harding Place (Box 77)
        - Munson Street, Orchard Street (Box 78)
        - Norton Parkway, Norton Street, Pond Street, Osborn Avenue (Box 79)
        - Royden Road, Ruby Street, Sherman Avenue or Parkway (Box 80)
        - Willis Street, West Division Street, Stimson Road, Ford Street (Box 81)
      - District 9
        - Argyle Street, Bassett Street (Box 82)
        - Dixwell Avenue (East side, odd number street addresses 383-397 through 787) (Box 83)
        - Dixwell Avenue (East side, non-street number files) (Box 84)
        - Division Street (Box 85)
        - Thompson Street (Box 86)
        - Gem Street, Read Street (Box 87)
        - Watson Street, West Read Street, Butler Street (Box 88)
        - Gibbs Street, Hazel Street (Box 89)
        - Goodyear Street, Lilac Street (Box 90)
        - Huntington Street, Munson Street (Box 91)
        - Ivy Street (Box 92)
        - Newhall Street (Street addresses 10-12 through 250) (Box 93)
        - Newhall Street (Street addresses 251 to 393-395), Shepard Street (Box 94)
        - Starr Street (Box 95)
        - Shelton Avenue (East side, odd number street addresses 7-9-11 through 433) (Box 96)
        - Shelton Avenue (West side, even number street addresses 34 through 426-428, non-street number files) (Box 97)
        - Winchester Avenue (West side, street addresses 488 through 916-918), Brewster Street (Box 98)
        - Winchester Avenue, (West side, non-street number files), Cave Street, Daisy Street, Lander Street (Box 99)
          Winchester Avenue, (West side, non-street number files), includes deeds of: Nathan B. Ives, David L. Daggett, James A. Wood, Henrietta E. Hooker, George T. Newhall, T. D. Read, Charles T. Shelton, "254 building lots".
      - District 10
        - Auburn Street, Chapel Street (Box 100)
        - Batter Terrace, Day Street, Dwight Street (Box 101)
        - Boulevard, Ellsworth Avenue, Fayette Street, Greenwood Street (Box 102)
        - Derby Avenue (Box 103)
        - George Street (Street addresses 501 through 689) (Box 104)
        - George Street (Street addresses 706 through 800, non-street number files) (Box 105)
        - Gilbert Avenue, Irving Street (Box 106)
        - Judson Avenue, Mead Street, Parmelee Avenue (Box 107)
        - Legion Avenue (Street addresses 115-117 through 767) (Box 108)
        - Miller Street, Norton Street, Porter Street, Scranton Street (Box 109)
        - Orchard Street (Box 110)
        - Sherman Avenue (Box 111)
        - Tyler Street, Waverly Street, West River, Wight Street, Winthrop Avenue (Box 112)
      - District 11
        - Chapel Street, Dwight Street (Box 113)
        - Crown Street (Box 114)
        - George Street, Howe Street, Park Street, York Street (Box 115)
      - District 12
        - Dwight Street, George Street, Howe Street (Box 116)
        - Oak Street, Park Street, Spruce Street, York Street (Box 117)
      - District 13
        - Broad Street, Commerce Street (Box 118)
        - Congress Avenue, Dow Street, Factory Street (Box 119)
        - George Street (Box 120)
        - Oak Street, Temple Street, York Street (Box 121)
      - District 14
        - Broad Street, Cedar Street, Congress Avenue (Box 122)
        - Block J -Parcels 1-21, College Street (bounded by Congress Avenue on south, Lafayette Street on east, Rose Street on northwest) (Box 123)
        - Davenport Avenue, Howard Avenue, Park Street, York Street (Box 124)
        - Kilgay Alley, Lafayette Street, Palmer Street, Rose Street, South Street (Box 125)
        - Oak Street (Box 126)
      - District 15
        - Asylum Street, Auburn Street, Boulevard, Sherman Avenue (Box 127)
        - Davenport Avenue, Howard Avenue (Box 128)
        - Elliott Street, Vernon Street (Box 129)
        - Evergreen Court, Greenwood Street, Legion Avenue, Oak Street (Box 130)
        - Orchard Street, Porter Street (Box 131)
        - Stevens Street (Street addresses 13 through 48) (Box 132)
        - Stevens Street (Street addresses 50 through 80, non-street number files), Tyler Street (Box 133)
        - Sylvan Avenue (Box 134)
        - Vine Street, Ward Street (Box 135)
        - Winthrop Avenue (Box 136)
      - District 16
        - Ann Street, Asylum Street, Baldwin Street (Box 137)
        - Congress Avenue, Sylvan Avenue (Box 138)
        - Davenport Avenue (Box 139)
        - Howard Avenue, Kossuth Street (Box 140)
        - Vernon Street, Ward Street, West Street (Box 141)
      - District 17
        - Arch Street (Street addresses 3 through 84-90) (Box 142)
        - Arch Street (Non-street number files), Daggett Street (Box 143)
        - Bond Street, Columbus Street, Redfield Street (Box 144)
        - Congress Street (Street addresses 420 through 798) (Box 145)
        - Congress Street (Street addresses 824 through 910, non-street number files), Downes Street (Box 146)
        - Hallock Street, Howard Avenue (Box 147)
        - Stevens Al., Washington Avenue, Washington Place, West Lane, West Street, White Street (Box 148)
      - District 18
        - Columbus Avenue, Congress Avenue (Box 149)
        - Cedar Street, Gilbert Street, Gold Street (Box 150)
        - Howard Avenue, Lafayette Street, Silver Street (Box 151)
        - Liberty Street (Box 152)
        - Minor Avenue, Prince Street, Washington Avenue (Street addresses 1 through 95) (Box 153)
        - Washington Avenue (Street addresses 96-104 through 289-291, non-street number files) (Box 154)
      - District 19
        - Boulevard, Hallock Avenue (Street addresses 14-16 through 192) (Box 155)
        - Hallock Avenue (Street addresses 194 through 300, non-street number files) (Box 156)
        - Fifth Street, First Street, Fourth Street, Sea Street, Second Street, Sixth Street (Box 157)
        - Lamberton Street, South Water Street (Box 158)
        - Greenwich Avenue (West side, even number street addresses 124-138 through 488-490), Grant Street (Box 159)
        - Greenwich Avenue (East side, odd number street addresses 101-103 through 457), Third Street (Box 160)
        - Howard Avenue (East side, odd number street addresses 19 through 367-369, non-street number files) (Box 161)
        - Howard Avenue (West side, even number street addresses 20-22 through 364-368-374, non-street number files) (Box 162)
        - Kimberly Avenue (Street addresses 3 through 267) (Box 163)
        - Kimberly Avenue (Non-street number files, miscellaneous records) (Box 164)
        - Plymouth Street (Box 165)
      - District 20
        - Columbus Avenue, Commerce Street, Congress Avenue, Lafayette Street (Box 166)
        - Hill Street, South Orange Street (Box 167)
        - Meadow Street, Prince Street, Silver Street, Water Street, West Water Street, Whiting Street (Box 168)
      - District 21
        - Carlisle Street (Box 169)
        - Cassius Street, Christopher Street, Loop Road, Rosette Street (Box 170)
        - Columbus Avenue, Howard Avenue (Box 171)
        - Edgar Street, Lamberton Street, Liberty Street, Salem Street, Union Avenue (Box 172)
        - Putnam Avenue (Box 173)
        - Portsea Street (Box 174)
        - Spring Street, West Water Street (Box 175)
        - Cedar Street, Water Street (Box 176)
      - District 22
        - Adeline Street, Alling Street, Arthur Street (Box 177)
        - Arthur Street (Box 178)
        - Barclay Street, Boulevard, Washington Avenue (Street addresses 383 through 509) (Box 179)
        - Washington Avenue (Street addresses 517-527 through 745, non-street number files) (Box 180)
        - Clover Place, Eddy Street, Hedge Street, Hurlburt Street (Box 181)